<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>D3.js on Ethan Nelson - Data Reporter</title>
    <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/tags/d3.js/</link>
    <description>Recent content in D3.js on Ethan Nelson - Data Reporter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 20:35:51 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ethannelson.github.io/tags/d3.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Traffic Crash Map</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/crashes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 20:35:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/crashes/</guid>
      <description>A map of traffic crashes in Chicago, according to time of day and estimated cost of damage. This make use of a combination of d3.js and Mapbox.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Investment in Africa Has Exploded Since 2008</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 21:19:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/africa/</guid>
      <description>National Security Advisor John Bolton recently unveiled the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s new strategy in Africa. It&amp;rsquo;s in part designed to counter the influence of Chinese investment in the continent. Below is a d3.js graphic exploring the trend. This graphic uses data from the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies&amp;rsquo; China Africa Research Initiative
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Americans are set to spend more on their pets than they have since 2001</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:03:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/pets/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this article by the New York Times, in which home decor and consumer news writer Michelle Higgins tells us about ways to spy on your dogs, I took a look at how much Americans spend on their domestic animals each year.
Americans are set to spend more on their pets in 2018 then they have in any of the past 16 years. Collectively, Americans are expected to spend more than $72 billion this year according to data from the American Pet Products Association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Place Names</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/place-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 18:05:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/place-names/</guid>
      <description>An interactive d3.js map of the location quotient of select place name components by county. This is not an exhaustive list of place names, but it does show some neat patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black coaches vanish from Big Ten basketball, once a model for diversity</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/basketball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 19:30:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/basketball/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, there were no nonwhite men&amp;rsquo;s basketball coaches in the Big Ten, the first time that had happened since the &amp;lsquo;80s. This is a story exploring the historical racial makeup in men&amp;rsquo;s college basketball. I did the analysis and made the graphics for this story by college basketball beat reporter Marcus Fuller. This story won an award from the National Association of Black Journalists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Average Gophers football attendance falls after 30-year high</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/gophers-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 21:28:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/gophers-football/</guid>
      <description>After near-record numbers, average Gophers football attendance fell in 2016. The team&amp;rsquo;s coach chalked it up to the Gophs&amp;rsquo; poor record. I used a static graphic made with d3.js to explain the trend for the Minnesota Daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See which U of M Classes Fared Best in Their Course Evaluations</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/class-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 12:48:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/class-ratings/</guid>
      <description>The data behind University of Minnesota students&amp;rsquo; course evaluations has been requested for years, but only recently became publicly available. This scatter plot, which didn&amp;rsquo;t look entirely great within the confines of the Daily&amp;rsquo;s CMS, details class evaluations for classes in 2015. Fun fact: Elementary Akkadian was one of the only courses to get a perfect score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University plan to trim admin costs appears to be ahead of schedule</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/administrative-expenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 21:16:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/administrative-expenses/</guid>
      <description>After a report accused the University of Minnesota of administrative bloat, the school planned to cut millions in spending. This is a story I helped explain with data analysis and a d3.js graphic with MN Daily reporter Kevin Beckman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kills Minneapolis Residents?</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/deaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:53:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/deaths/</guid>
      <description>I used data from the City of Minneapolis and d3.js to make an interactive explaining what kills Minneapolis residents. A bit morbid, maybe. This is based on a dashboard from the d3 wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota sex-ed programs go unregulated</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/sexed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 13:00:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/sexed/</guid>
      <description>This was a d3.js map that intitially ran alongside a Minnesota Daily project about sex ed. The Daily&amp;rsquo;s shift to a new CMS resulted in the graphic falling off, but it&amp;rsquo;s preserved on the newspaper&amp;rsquo;s github account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota Student Election Turnout on the Rise</title>
      <link>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/uminn-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 12:44:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethannelson.github.io/posts/uminn-elections/</guid>
      <description>Voter turnout for the University of Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s student elections had been rising over the past few years in 2016. Using c3.js, I detailed this trend for both graduate students and undergraduates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>